Guide to the Samuel J. Tilden papers, 1794-1886 [bulk 1835-1876]
The New York Public Library. Manuscripts and Archives Division.
- Series III. Legal Files, 1832 - 1891, n.d.; 39720; 20 boxes, 3 volumes; 8.6 linear feet
  - III. E. Burdell estate case, 1856 - 1873, n.d.; 39753
    Includes files generated by Tilden and his office in the course of a Surrogate Court case brought by George D. Bulen and his wife, two of several heirs to Dr. Harvey Burdell, against Burdell's estate, seeking recompense for expenses incurred in defense of the estate during the Cunningham-Burdell murder case.
    - Correspondence, 1856 - 1864, n.d.; 39754 (Box 50, Folder 6-9)
    - Case files, 1857 - 1873, n.d.; 39755
      - 1857, 39756 (Box 50, Folder 10-11)
      - 1857, 39757 (Box 51, Folder 1-2)
      - 1858 - 1859, 39758 (Box 51, Folder 3)
      - 1860, 39759 (Box 51, Folder 4-6)
      - 1861 - 1873, 39760 (Box 51, Folder 7)
      - Undated, 39761 (Box 51, Folder 8)
      - Undated, 39762 (Box 52, Folder 1-2)
  - III. F. Miscellaneous legal files, 1832 - 1891, n.d.; 39763
    These files represent many of Tilden's smaller, less publicized cases. Also included are deeds, affidavits, articles of incorporation, power of attorney, and other documents generated in his legal practice. Not all opinions and arguments in the general files were written by Tilden. Files are arranged chronologically.
    - John and George Hecker vs. New York Balance Dock Co., 1852 - 1857; 39764 (Box 52, Folder 3)
    - New York City Board of Education vs. Azariah C. Flagg, 1856; 39765 (Box 52, Folder 4)
    - Richard S. Roberts vs. New York Balance Dock Co., 1857; 39766 (Box 52, Folder 5-6)
    - Robert Bayard vs. Edwin Ludlow, 1857 - 1858; 39767 (Box 52, Folder 7)
    - Hubbard G. Stone vs. New York City Board of Education, 1858; 39768 (Box 53, Folder 1)
    - Raymond vs. Sherman, 1859; 39769 (Box 53, Folder 2)
    - Chicago, Alton & St. Louis Railroad, 1859 - 1866, 1879; 39770 (Box 53, Folder 3-6)
    - Gulick vs. New York Balance Dock Co., 1860 - 1862; 39771 (Box 53, Folder 7-8)
    - Azariah C. Flagg vs. Terre Haute Rail Road, 1862; 39772; See also: Series X: Personal Papers, which includes files relating to Tilden's business and legal relationship to the Terre Haute, Alton & St. Louis Rail Road. (Box 54, Folder 1)
    - Atlantic & Great Western Railway, 1866 - 1869; 39773 (Box 54, Folder 2-3)
    - Hatch vs. Pritchard, 1867; 39774 (Box 54, Folder 4-5)
    - Pacific Mail Steamship Company injunction, 1867 - 1868; 39775 (Box 54, Folder 6)
    - Chicago & Great Western Railway, 1868; 39776 (Box 54, Folder 7-8)
    - Fisk vs. Union Pacific Railroad Company, 1869 - 1870; 39777 (Box 55, Folder 1-2)
    - New Jersey Midway Railroad Company, 1870 - 1871; 39778 (Box 55, Folder 3)
    - Erie Railway Company, 1872 - 1875; 39779 (Box 55, Folder 4)
    - Spencer contested election, 1875 - 1876; 39780 (Box 55, Folder 5-7)
    - Spencer contested election, 1875 - 1876; 39781 (Box 56, Folder 1)
    - Arguments, 1839, 1870, n.d; 39782 (Box 56, Folder 2)
    - Opinions {1860 - 1873, n.d.}@, 39783 (Box 56, Folder 3-4)
    - Railroads, 1851 - 1884, n.d.; 39784 (Box 56, Folder 5)
    - Receipts, 1847 - 1891, n.d.; 39785 (Box 56, Folder 1)
    - Resolutions, 1838 - 1884, n.d.; 39786 (Box 57, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous documents, 1845 - 1871, n.d.; 39787 (Box 57, Folder 3)
  - III. G. Registers and indices, 1841 - 1865, n.d.; 39788
    Bound volumes include a complaint book, a log of judgments obtained, a register of cases, and an index of his cases from 1841 to 1865.
    - Complaint book, undated; 39789 (Box 57, Folder 4)
    - Index to cases, 1841 - 1865; 39790 (Volume 5)
    - Register of cases, 1841 - 1861; 39791 (Volume 6)
    - Register of cases, 1861 - 1865; 39792 (Volume 7)
- Series IV. Democratic Republican party and Free-Soil movement, 1832 - 1853, n.d.; 39793; 1 folder (Box 57, Folder 5)
  When the the Democratic Party split over the issue of slavery, Tilden supported the more radical Barnburners. The Barnburners allied themselves with Whigs and Abolitionists to form the Free-Soil Party, which successfully ran his long-time ally Martin Van Buren as a third-party candidate.
  Material representing Tilden's activities with the Democratic Republican Party and the Free-Soil Movement includes meeting minutes, by-laws, and drafts of a plan of organization of the Democratic Republican Party for the election of 1844.
- Series V. Democratic National Committee, 1868 - 1872; 39794; 1 folder (Box 57, Folder 6)
  Tilden served as a delegate to the 1864 and 1868 Democratic National Conventions, and as New York Democratic State Chair from 1872-1882.
  Very little material concerning the Democratic National Committee has been preserved in this collection. Extant material includes circulars and printed material relating to the Democratic party, and to the Democratic National Conventions of 1868 and 1872.
- Series VI. Tweed Ring, 1868 - 1875; 39795; 5 boxes, 2 linear feet
  William M. "Boss" Tweed had long asserted himself in New York politics, but remained largely ignored by Tilden until he introduced a new city charter which would give him considerable power and access to taxpayer funds. Tilden, as chairman of the Democratic State Committee, exposed Tweed's corruption and brought an end to one of the most powerful political administrations in the history of the United States.
  Tilden's actions against the Tweed Ring are represented through Financial and Legal files. The Financial files represent forensic accounting of Tweed's shell companies performed by banks and by members of Tilden's office. Material includes deposit slips, cancelled checks, ledgers, and "Statements of Plunder." In addition to William M. Tweed, other notable figures subjected to Tilden's audits include James H. Ingersoll, Ingersoll & Co., New York Printing Company, Richard Connolly, A. J. Smith, and Peter B. and James M. Sweeney. Also includes an analysis of city expenditures to 1871, and registers of county liabilities.
  Legal files include a bill of complaint against James H. Ingersoll, and a copy of Judge Allen's opinion on the case against Ingersoll & Co., one of the Tweed Ring's largest shell companies. Also contained here are the opinions of Judge Folger regarding the People v. Thomas C. Field et. al; a transcript of Tilden's testimony in the Tweed trial; memoranda regarding Peter B. Sweeney's money transferring activities; subpoenas; and drafts of legislation aimed at "providing more effectual remedies in cases of the fraudulent acquisition, payment, disposition, or conversion of public money or property."
  Additional material related to the Tweed Ring may also be found in Series I.
  - Financial files, 1868 - 1875; 39796
    - Adjusted claims, 39797 (Box 57, Folder 7)
    - Cardozo, Albert, 39798 (Box 57, Folder 8)
    - City of New York, 39799 (Box 57, Folder 9)
    - Connolly, Richard B., 39800 (Box 58, Folder 1)
    - Corson, Cornelius, 39801 (Box 58, Folder 2)
    - County liabilities, 39802 (Box 58, Folder 3)
    - Garvey, Andrew J., 39803 (Box 58, Folder 4)
    - Ingersoll, James, 39804 (Box 58, Folder 5-6)
    - Miller, George S., 39805 (Box 58, Folder 7)
    - New York Printing Company, 39806 (Box 58, Folder 8)
    - Smith, Andrew J., 39807 (Box 59, Folder 1-2)
    - Smith, Hugh, 39808 (Box 59, Folder 3)
    - Smith, James W., 39809 (Box 59, Folder 4)
    - Sweeney, James M., 39810 (Box 59, Folder 5-6)
    - Sweeney, Peter B., 39811 (Box 59, Folder 7)
    - Tweed, William Marcy, 39812 (Box 59, Folder 8)
    - Watson, James, 39813 (Box 59, Folder 9)
    - Wilbour, Charles E., 39814 (Box 59, Folder 10)
    - Woodward, E.A., 39815 (Box 59, Folder 11)
    - Young, Jason B., 39816 (Box 59, Folder 12)
    - Statements of division of plunder, 39817; Oversized. (Box 92, Folder 1-2)
    - Forensic accounting, 1868 - 1875; 39818 (Box 60, Folder 1-5)
    - Cancelled checks, 1868 - 1875; 39819 (Box 60, Folder 6)
    - Deposit slips, 1868 - 1875; 39820 (Box 61, Folder 1-4)
  - Legal files, 1869 - 1875, n.d.; 39821
    - 1869 - 1871, 39822 (Box 62, Folder 1)
    - 1872, 39823 (Box 62, Folder 2-3)
    - 1873, 39824 (Box 62, Folder 4)
    - 1875, 39825 (Box 62, Folder 5)
    - Undated, 39826 (Box 62, Folder 6-7)
- Series VII. New York State Assembly, 1872 - 1873, n.d.; 39827; 1 box, .5 linear feet
  Tilden was elected to the New York State Assembly in 1846 and again in 1872. He used his position to take on corruption in state government, most notably through the impeachment of Tweed's associates in the New York State Supreme Court: Justices George G. Barnard, Albert Cardozo, and John H. McCunn.
  Tilden's 1872 term in the New York State Assembly is represented by files documenting the impeachment of three New York State Supreme Court Justices; by one file of material relating to New York City charter reform; and by material relating to the exposure of corruption within the Customs House. Correspondence relating to the New York State Assembly may be found in Series I.
  - Impeachment of Judges Barnard, Cardozo, and McCunn, 1872; 39828 (Box 62, Folder 8-9)
  - Impeachment of Judges Barnard, Cardozo, and McCunn, 1872; 39829 (Box 63, Folder 1)
  - New York City charter revision, ca. 1872; 39830 (Box 63, Folder 2)
  - Customs House Ring, 1873; 39831 (Box 63, Folder 3)
- Series VIII. Gubernatorial files, 1864 - 1877, n.d.; 39832; 6 boxes, 2.5 linear feet
  In 1874, Tilden won the gubernatorial election against respected a popular incumbent. However, his legislative efforts were hampered by the Republican majority in the State Legislature.
  The Gubernatorial Papers consist of files maintained and material collected by Tilden during his term of office. His successful effort to break up the Canal Ring is reflected through financial reports, legal files, and printed matter. Executive files cover a range of topics such as canals, railroads, demographics and statistics, remarks on assembly bills, and vetoes. Legislation drafted or enacted during Tilden's tenure is represented in the legislative files, which include drafts, often in multiple iterations, of bills relating to annexation and incorporation of towns and villages, appropriations, political reform, and public health.
  - VIII. A. Canal Ring, 1866 - 1875; 39833
    One of Tilden's most notable accomplishments while in office was the dismantling of the Canal Ring, a cabal of politicians and contractors who had been defrauding the state by submitting inflated invoices for repairs and improvements.
    Financial material includes ledgers, accounts, and logs kept by Tilden during his investigation of graft in the New York canal system. Reports define the cost of ordinary and extraordinary repairs to canals; shipping statements document the cost of transporting wood, grains, and other commodities. Legal material includes resolutions by political groups and trade organizations in support of Tilden's exposure of the ring; trial notes; legislative material related to the trial and investigation; and the depositions of William Dorsheimer, Alexander P. Berthand, William H. Talcott, Charles Stebbins, and Lewis R. Davis. Printed material refers to contract blanks, circulars, notices to contractors, and an annotated partial transcript of the Canal Ring trial.
    - Financial material, 1868 - 1875; 39834 (Box 63, Folder 4-7)
    - Legal material, 1875; 39835 (Box 63, Folder 8-9)
    - Reports and memoranda, 1875; 39836 (Box 64, Folder 1-5)
    - Printed material, 1866 - 1875; 39837 (Box 64, Folder 6)
  - VIII. B. Executive papers, 1874 - 1877, n.d.; 39838
    The Executive Papers were compiled during Tilden's tenure as Governor of the State of New York, and cover a number of topics through reports and memoranda including state finances, prisons and asylums, schools, the National Guard, public health, immigration, canals, and railroads.
    - Relating to capitol building, 1875 - 1876; 39839 (Box 65, Folder 1)
    - Relating to constitutional amendments, 1874; 39840 (Box 65, Folder 2)
    - Demographics and statistics, undated; 39841 (Box 65, Folder 3)
    - Fire Commissioners' investigation, 1874 - 1876; 39842 (Box 65, Folder 4-6)
    - Relating to jails and asylums, 1875 - 1876; 39843 (Box 65, Folder 7)
    - Petitions, 1874 - 1880; 39844; Oversize material, rolled. (Box 92)
    - Police Commissioners' investigation, 1875; 39845 (Box 65, Folder 8)
    - Relating to railroads, 1875 - 1876; 39846 (Box 66, Folder 1)
    - Relating to state finances, 1875 - 1876; 39847 (Box 66, Folder 2-3)
    - Remarks on assembly bills, 1875 - 1876; 39848 (Box 66, Folder 4)
    - Rosters, 1875 - 1876; 39849 (Box 66, Folder 5-6)
    - Vetoes, 1875 - 1876; 39850 (Box 67, Folder 1)
    - General files, 1874 - 1877, n.d.; 39851 (Box 67, Folder 2-3)
  - VIII. C. Legislative files, 1864 - 1876; 39852
    Legislative files relate to bills enacted or under consideration during Tilden's tenure as governor. Files contain drafts of assembly bills, as well as final versions submitted to the legislature, petitions, and supporting material. Topics covered include supply and appropriations bills; incorporation and annexation of land; armories and militia; schools, asylums and prisons; political appointments and reform; and legislation relating to the City of New York and to Kings County (Brooklyn). Also includes annotated rosters of counties, assembly districts, towns and election districts.
    - An Act to Incorporate the Sisterhood of Grey Nuns, 1875; 39853 (Box 67, Folder 4)
    - An Act to Prevent the Adulteration of Milk, 1864, 1875; 39854 (Box 67, Folder 5)
    - Annexation and incorporation, 1875 - 1876; 39855 (Box 67, Folder 6)
    - Appropriations, 1875 - 1876; 39856 (Box 67, Folder 7)
    - Armories and militia, 1875 - 1876; 39857 (Box 67, Folder 8)
    - Canals, 1875 - 1876; 39858 (Box 67, Folder 9-10)
    - Canals, undated; 39859 (Box 68, Folder 1)
    - City of Elmira, 1875 - 1876; 39860 (Box 68, Folder 2)
    - City of New York, 1875 - 1876; 39861 (Box 68, Folder 3)
    - City of Rochester, 1875 - 1876; 39862 (Box 68, Folder 4)
    - Education, 1874 - 1876; 39863 (Box 68, Folder 5)
    - Elevated railways, 1874 - 1875; 39864 (Box 68, Folder 6)
    - Jails, prisons, and asylums, 1872; n.d.; 39865 (Box 68, Folder 7)
    - Kings County, 1875; 39866 (Box 68, Folder 8)
    - Political appointments and reform, 1875 - 1876; 39867 (Box 68, Folder 9)
    - Public safety, 1875; 39868 (Box 68, Folder 10)
    - Public works, 1875 - 1876; 39869 (Box 68, Folder 11)
    - Salt springs, 1875 - 1876; 39870 (Box 68, Folder 12)
    - State Treasury, 1875 - 1876; 39871 (Box 68, Folder 13)
    - Supply Bills, 1875 - 1876; 39872 (Box 68, Folder 14)
    - Taxes, 1876; 39873 (Box 68, Folder 15)
    - The West Point Bill, 1875 Mar - May; 39874 (Box 68, Folder 16)
    - Miscellaneous legislation, 1874 - 1876, n.d.; 39875 (Box 69, Folder 1)
- Series IX. Presidential election of 1876, 1876 - 1878; 39876; 3 boxes, 1.25 linear feet
  Tilden was the Democratic candidate for President in 1876. He won the popular vote, but the electoral vote went to Rutherford B. Hayes. After an investigation into the activities of the Electoral College, Tilden conceded the election.
  This series focuses on the aftermath of the 1876 Presidential election, particularly the recount of the electoral ballots. Some campaign material is extent, but the series is predominantly comprised of official voting returns from the Electoral Colleges of various states. Files for some states, particularly Florida and Louisiana, contain reports, memoranda, and other supporting documentation of the Tilden camp's research into election fraud or elector misconduct in those states. Such material includes drafts of related legislation, research on legal precedents, affidavits, and minutes of the proceedings of the Florida Electoral College.
  - Campaign material, 1876-80; 39877 (Box 69, Folder 2)
  - State files, 1876 - 1878; 39878
    - Alabama, 1876; 39879 (Box 69, Folder 3)
    - Connecticut, 1876; 39880 (Box 69, Folder 4)
    - Deleware, 1876; 39881 (Box 69, Folder 5)
    - Florida, 1876 - 1878; 39882 (Box 69, Folder 6-8)
    - Georgia, 1876; 39883 (Box 69, Folder 9)
    - Indiana, 1876; 39884 (Box 69, Folder 10)
    - Kentucky, 1876; 39885 (Box 69, Folder 11)
    - Louisiana, 1876; 39886 (Box 69, Folder 12)
    - Mississippi, 1876; 39887 (Box 69, Folder 13)
    - Missouri, 1876; 39888 (Box 69, Folder 14)
    - New York, 1876; 39889 (Box 69, Folder 15)
    - North Carolina, 1876; 39890 (Box 70, Folder 1)
    - Oregon, 1876; 39891 (Box 70, Folder 2)
    - Pennyslvania, 1876; 39892 (Box 70, Folder 3)
    - South Carolina, 1876; 39893 (Box 70, Folder 4)
    - Tennessee, 1876; 39894 (Box 70, Folder 5)
    - Texas, 1876; 39895 (Box 70, Folder 6)
    - Virginia, 1876; 39896 (Box 70, Folder 7)
    - West Virginia, 1876; 39897 (Box 70, Folder 8)
  - General files, 1876 - 1877; 39898 (Box 70, Folder 9-10)
  - Pamphlets relating to the counting of electoral ballots, 1876 - 1887; 39899 (Box 71, Folder 1)
- Series X. Writings and Speeches, ca. 1820s - 1886, n.d; 39900; 9 boxes, 3.75 linear feet.
  This series contains both manuscript drafts and published copies of Tilden's writings and speeches. Published copies are often annotated or corrected. One folder of interviews with Tilden is also included, as is an index of his published speeches. Some unidentified material cannot be definitively attributed to Tilden, and due to the prolific nature of his writing, this series is not necessarily a complete representation of his work.
  - X. A. Writings, ca. 1820s - 1886, n.d; 39901
    The writings preserved in the collection date from Tilden's school years up until his death. An 1833 essay on the presidency of Martin Van Buren gained him early prominence in New York's Democratic circles, while an article entitled Coercive Temperance Law and the Democratic Candidate for Attorney General decries the "barbarian" paternalism of the Temperance movement. In the years of political unrest leading up to the Civil War, Tilden wrote vehemently on The Union!! Its Dangers!! And How They Can Be Averted, and outlined his opinion on the war between the States in an 1862 memorandum. Much of the writing contained herein relates to the Tweed Ring, including a letter to the Evening Post, drafts of a manuscript covering the events of the investigation and trial, and even a prose play, The Drama of the Ring. Later writings include a statement to the press regarding the "cipher telegrams," a vote-buying scandal centering on his nephew, Col. William Tilden Pelton, and his letter declining the nomination for the presidency in 1880. Most of the early writings are quite fragmentary, while later writings are generally represented by more complete drafts.
    - Juvenilia and early writings, ca. 1820s - 1830s; 39902
      - Juvenalia and early writings, ca. 1820s - 1830s; 39903 (Box 71, Folder 2-4)
      - Juvenalia and early writings, undated; 39904 (Box 72, Folder 1)
    - General writings, 1832 - 1886; 39905
      - The Coalition, 1832; 39906 (Box 72, Folder 2)
      - The Indian Question, 1832; 39907 (Box 72, Folder 3)
      - On Martin Van Buren, 1833; 39908 (Box 72, Folder 4)
      - Defeat of the Democracy, or The Political Reaction, 1840; 39909 (Box 72, Folder 5)
      - Is The U.S. Bank Charter Appealable?, 1841; 39910 (Box 72, Folder 6)
      - Plan for county and town organization, 1841; 39911 (Box 72, Folder 7)
      - Mr. Greeley, The Legislation, and The Slavery Question, 1849; 39912 (Box 72, Folder 8)
      - On expansion of currency, ca. 1840s; 39913 (Box 72, Folder 9)
      - Anticipation of canal revenues and the Constitution, 1851; 39914 (Box 72, Folder 10)
        Includes reprint of pamphlet Pay As You Go! or The Unconstitutionality of the Nine Million Dollar Debt Bill Demonstrated published by William Cullen Bryant {1851}
      - Prospectus of the Fourney-Caterer, 1853; 39915 (Box 72, Folder 11)
      - The Coercive Temperance Law and the Democratic Candidate for Attorney General of the State, 1855; 39916; Reprints in English and German (Box 72, Folder 12)
      - Letters to the Editors, 1860 - 1873, n.d.; 39917 (Box 72, Folder 13)
      - The Union! Its Dangers!! And How They Can Be Averted, 1860; 39918; Reprint (Box 72, Folder 14)
      - Memorandum on the Civil War, 1862; 39919 (Box 72, Folder 15)
      - Political circulars, 1868 - 1879; 39920 (Box 72, Folder 16)
      - Tweed Ring, 1868 - 1874, n.d.; 39921
        - Letter to The Evening Post, 1868; 39922 (Box 72, Folder 17)
        - Drafts of letters to Charles O'Conor, 39923 (Box 72, Folder 18)
        - The Tweed Ring, 1871 -1873; 39924 (Box 73, Folder 1-7)
        - The Drama of the Ring, ca. 1871 - 1873; 39925 (Box 73, Folder 8)
        - Relating to Tweed defendants appealing the overruling of a demurrer, 1872; 39926 (Box 74, Folder 1-2)
        - untitled, 1872; 39927 (Box 74, Folder 3)
        - Relating to Ingersoll case, 1874; 39928 (Box 74, Folder 4)
        - Miscellaneous drafts and unidentified material, undated; 39929 (Box 74, Folder 5)
      - Editorial for The World, 1869; 39930 (Box 74, Folder 6)
      - Impeachment, its Nature and Object, 1872; 39931 (Box 74, Folder 7)
      - Reply to New York Times article, 1873; 39932 (Box 74, Folder 8)
      - Memorandum to William H. Wickham, 1875; 39933 (Box 74, Folder 9)
        On removals from office.
      - Messages of the Governor of the State of New York, 1875; 39934; Reprint (Box 74, Folder 10)
      - Special message to the Commissioners of Immigration, 1876; 39935 (Box 75, Folder 1)
      - Drafts of resolutions to Congress relating to the election of 1876, 39936 (Box 75, Folder 2)
      - Article on Rutherford B. Hayes' confession to his cabinet, ca. 1876 - 1878; 39937 (Box 75, Folder 3)
      - Statement to press relating to the cypher telegrams, 1878; 39938 (Box 75, Folder 4)
      - Letter of declension for the Presidential nomination, 1880; 39939 (Box 75, Folder 5)
      - The Monroe Doctrine and its Origins, 1885; 39940 (Box 75, Folder 6)
      - The Accountability of Corporations, 1886; 39941 (Box 75, Folder 7)
      - Preface to speech by Edward Livingston, 1886; 39942 (Box 75, Folder 8)
      - Account of the fire of 1835, n.d.; 39943 (Box 74, Folder 9)
      - Edward Curtis and the Electoral Frauds, 39944 (Box 75, Folder 10)
      - Essay on canals, n.d.; 39945 (Box 75, Folder 11)
      - Give Anderson a Fresh Trial, 39946 (Box 75, Folder 12)
      - How the Political Result of 1840 was Effected, n.d.; 39947 (Box 75, Folder 13)
      - On laws governing Mississippi and Alabama, 39948 (Box 75, Folder 14)
      - Mr. Douglas' Bill, n.d.; 39949 (Box 75, Folder 15)
      - Relating to the nomination of Martin Van Buren, n.d.; 39950 (Box 75, Folder 16)
      - Resolution Against the Establishment of a National Bank, n.d.; 39951 (Box 75, Folder 17)
      - Rights of Electors, n.d.; 39952 (Box 75, Folder 18)
      - Unidentified fragments, ca. 1830s-1840s, n.d; 39953 (Box 75, Folder 19-22)
  - X. B. Speeches, 1831 - 1880, n.d.; 39954